Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine.
我是Catherine。
And today we have a very healthy lesson for everyone.
今天我们要给大家带来一堂非常健康的课程。
We are going to have healthy food.
我们要聊聊健康食品。
So we're going to the grocery store and we're choosing what food to buy.
所以我们要去杂货店，挑选要买的食物。
You're going to hear a lot of words about eating right and eating healthy.
你会听到很多关于正确饮食和健康饮食的词汇。
So let's jump into this dialogue first and we'll be back in a moment to talk more about
我们先来听一段对话，稍后再回来详细讨论
it.
它。
Okay darling, I got some pizzas, potato chips, hot dogs and lots of cheese.
好的亲爱的，我买了些披萨、薯片、热狗和很多奶酪。
Oh John, I thought we said we'd start eating right.
哦John，我以为我们说好要开始健康饮食了。
Remember?
记得吗？
Our new healthy lifestyle.
我们新的健康生活方式。
That's all junk food.
那些全是垃圾食品。
Huh.
哈。
Right, so what did you get?
好吧，那你买了什么？
Well healthy food, of course.
当然是健康食品啦。
I got some whole wheat bread, skimmed milk, fresh fish and organic carrots.
我买了些全麦面包、脱脂牛奶、新鲜鱼和有机胡萝卜。
Organic?
有机？
What's organic?
什么是有机？
Do we need organic carrots?
我们需要有机胡萝卜吗？
They were grown without using any chemicals that are harmful to our health.
它们是在没有使用任何有害健康的化学物质的情况下种植的。
And yes John, we need organic carrots.
而且是的John，我们需要有机胡萝卜。
Oh, so organic vegetables are the green option, right?
哦，所以有机蔬菜是绿色选择，对吧？
Yep, better for the environment and better for us.
对，对环境更好，对我们也好。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
What's that?
那是什么？
Donuts?
甜甜圈？
Are they organic donuts, Kelly?
它们是有机甜甜圈吗，Kelly？
But I like donuts.
但我喜欢甜甜圈。
So it's a very popular topic nowadays.
所以这是现在非常流行的话题。
People want to eat light.
人们想吃清淡的食物。
So why don't we take a look at some of these words and phrases now in Language Takeaway.
那我们现在在“语言小贴士”环节来看看这些单词和短语吧。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
The first kind of food we have here is whole wheat bread.
我们这里第一种食物是全麦面包。
So maybe you're buying bread at the grocery store and you see a number of different kinds
所以你可能在杂货店买面包时，会看到几种不同的
of bread.
面包。
There's white bread, there's rye bread.
有白面包、黑麦面包。
Well we have whole wheat bread which is maybe the healthiest option.
嗯，我们有全麦面包，这可能是最健康的选择。
So it's made out of wheat.
它是用小麦做的。
Alright so we have whole wheat bread.
好的，所以我们有全麦面包。
Now as you say, it's a type of bread that uses wheat as its main ingredient.
就像你说的，这是一种以小麦为主要成分的面包。
Right, so it's made from wheat flour.
对，它是用小麦粉做的。
It's usually a brownish kind of bread.
通常是一种褐色的面包。
That means the color is brown, not white.
意思是颜色是棕色的，不是白色的。
And it's healthier than white bread because white bread uses that processed flour, right?
而且它比白面包更健康，因为白面包用的是加工过的面粉，对吧？
It does.
是的。
It's processed and also uses a lot more sugar.
它是加工过的，而且用了更多的糖。
Okay, so whole wheat bread is a healthy option.
好的，所以全麦面包是一种健康的选择。
And also we are having skimmed milk.
我们还有脱脂牛奶。
Alright, so as you know when milk comes out of the cow, it's very very fatty.
好的，你知道牛奶从奶牛身上挤出来时，脂肪含量非常高。
There's lots of fat.
有很多脂肪。
And so skimmed milk means that when the dairy is processing the milk, the fat is taken away.
所以脱脂牛奶意味着乳制品加工牛奶时，脂肪被去掉了。
So this is one of the healthier kinds of milk.
所以这是比较健康的牛奶之一。
You have fat-free and skimmed milk which are the healthiest.
有脱脂牛奶和零脂牛奶，它们是最健康的。
So when you buy normal milk, what is that called?
那你买普通牛奶时，它叫什么？
Well you have whole milk.
嗯，有全脂牛奶。
Whole milk.
全脂牛奶。
And you also have 2% milk which is 2% fat.
还有2%的牛奶，含2%的脂肪。
And then skimmed milk and fat-free milk.
然后是脱脂牛奶和零脂牛奶。
Okay good.
好的。
Now when we were talking about the carrots, she said, you know what, we also bought organic
当我们谈到胡萝卜时，她说，你知道吗，我们还买了有机
carrots.
胡萝卜。
So this is a very popular word nowadays.
所以这是现在非常流行的词。
Organic vegetables, organic carrots.
有机蔬菜、有机胡萝卜。
What does it mean if it's organic?
有机是什么意思？
Well in general, things that are organic come from nature.
一般来说，有机的东西来自大自然。
But in food, things that are organic don't use chemicals.
但在食品中，有机的东西不使用化学物质。
So a lot of people are very nervous about food that comes from farms that have pesticides
所以很多人对来自使用杀虫剂
or chemicals on them.
或化学物质的农场的食物感到非常紧张。
But organic food is safe in this area.
但有机食品在这方面是安全的。
There's no pesticides or chemicals.
没有杀虫剂或化学物质。
Okay.
好的。
So what about when you talk about chickens or animals, they also say it's an organic
那当你谈到鸡或动物时，他们也会说是有机
farm.
农场。
That means that they don't have chemicals injected into them.
这意味着它们没有被注射化学物质。
That's right.
没错。
They're not stuffed with chemicals or given chemical shots.
它们没有被塞满化学物质或注射化学针剂。
And also the food that they eat is real food.
而且它们吃的食物是真正的食物。
It's not like chemical food to make them fatter.
不是为了让它们更胖而吃的化学饲料。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
So organic foods.
所以是有机食品。
And you mentioned the word chemicals a lot.
你刚才多次提到了“化学物质”这个词。
So when we talk about chemicals, we're talking about substances that are artificial, right?
所以当我们谈论化学物质时，我们指的是人造的物质，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
They're not organic.
它们不是有机的。
These are things that are chemicals that scientists come up with to help make food.
这些是科学家为了帮助生产食物而制造出来的化学物质。
For example, help make fatter chickens or to make greener vegetables.
比如，帮助养出更肥的鸡或让蔬菜更绿。
And these are not natural.
这些不是天然的。
These are man-made.
这些是人造的。
And chemicals can also mean pesticides.
化学物质也可以指杀虫剂。
So some sprays or things that we put on plants to keep the bugs away.
比如一些喷洒在植物上用来驱虫的喷雾或东西。
And these are all things that have been found to hurt human beings.
这些都被发现对人体有害。
Yeah.
是的。
I guess, for example, when you are eating something and you see in the box and it says
我想，比如，当你吃东西时，看到盒子上写着
it has certain preservatives, those are chemicals, right?
含有某些防腐剂，那些就是化学物质，对吧？
That help keep the food fresh for a longer period of time.
它们帮助食物保持新鲜更长时间。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So those are chemicals and that's the last word that we have for you on language takeaway.
所以这些就是化学物质，这也是我们在语言学习环节中为你准备的最后一个词。
Four key words here.
这里有四个关键词。
Why don't we go back, listen to the dialogue again, and we'll be back in a bit.
我们不如回去再听一遍对话，一会儿回来。
Okay darling, I got some pizzas, potato chips, hot dogs, and lots of cheese.
好的亲爱的，我买了些披萨、薯片、热狗和很多奶酪。
Oh John, I thought we said we'd start eating right.
哦约翰，我以为我们说好要开始健康饮食了。
Remember?
记得吗？
Our new healthy lifestyle.
我们新的健康生活方式。
That's all junk food.
那全是垃圾食品。
Hmm.
嗯。
Right.
对。
So what did you get?
那你买了什么？
Well, healthy food, of course.
嗯，当然是健康食品。
I got some whole wheat bread, skimmed milk, fresh fish, and organic carrots.
我买了些全麦面包、脱脂牛奶、鲜鱼和有机胡萝卜。
Organic?
有机？
What's organic?
什么是有机？
Do we need organic carrots?
我们需要有机胡萝卜吗？
They were grown without using any chemicals that are harmful to our health.
它们是在不使用任何对健康有害的化学物质的情况下种植的。
And yes, John, we need organic carrots.
是的，约翰，我们需要有机胡萝卜。
Oh, so organic vegetables are the green option, right?
哦，所以有机蔬菜是绿色选择，对吧？
Yep.
是的。
Better for the environment and better for us.
对环境更好，对我们也好。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
What's that?
那是什么？
Donuts?
甜甜圈？
Are they organic donuts, Kelly?
它们是有机甜甜圈吗，凯莉？
But I like donuts.
但我喜欢甜甜圈。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at three key phrases on Fluency Builder.
现在让我们看看流利表达环节中的三个关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利表达。
This first key phrase is one that I think was very, very common in America in the late
第一个关键短语我认为在80年代末、90年代初的美国非常非常常见。
80s, early 1990s.
美国人一直在努力吃健康食品，少吃高脂肪食物。
People in America have been struggling with eating healthy food and not eating so much
所以当时强调要“正确饮食”。
fatty food.
没错。
And so there was an emphasis on eating right.
正确饮食。
That's right.
那么，怎么才算正确饮食呢？
To eat right.
我的意思是，听起来像是要用勺子正确地吃饭。
Now, how do you eat right?
不，正确饮食更多是关于你吃的食物种类。
I mean, it sounds like you want to eat with your spoon correctly.
不是每天吃披萨、披萨和汉堡。
No, eating right is more about the kind of food you eat.
所以我们说正确饮食包括均衡的饮食。
It's about not eating pizza every day, pizza and hamburgers.
这意味着吃蔬菜、谷物、少量肉类，以及不太多的甜食
So we say eating right involves having a balanced diet.
或油脂。
That means eating vegetables and grains and a little bit of meat and not so many sweets
好的。
or oils.
所以这就是正确饮食的意思。
Okay.
所以你必须正确饮食。
So that's what it means when you are eating right.
这意味着吃健康的食物。
So you have to eat right.
现在相反的情况，如果你不健康饮食，那可能是因为你吃了太多
That means eating healthy.
垃圾食品。
Now the opposite, if you're not eating healthy, that's because maybe you're eating too much
这就是我们的下一个短语。
junk food.
对。
And that's our next phrase.
所以垃圾食品就是垃圾一样的食物。
Right.
对。
So junk food is junk garbage food.
垃圾食品就是垃圾一样的食物。
It's the kind of food that is very unhealthy for you.
这是一种对你非常不健康的食物。
Potato chips, pizza, ice cream.
薯片、披萨、冰淇淋。
It's all the best kind of food.
这些都是最好吃的食物。
But it's also the worst for your body.
但也是对身体最有害的。
So we call it junk food.
所以我们称之为垃圾食品。
Okay.
好的。
So everything that's, for example, fast food is usually considered to be junk food.
所以所有像快餐这样的东西通常都被认为是垃圾食品。
Yes, it's high in oils and fats.
是的，它富含油脂和脂肪。
Okay.
好的。
So junk food.
所以是垃圾食品。
And for the last phrase for today.
然后是今天的最后一个短语。
What is it?
是什么？
And for the last phrase, we are starting a healthy lifestyle.
最后一个短语，我们开始谈论健康的生活方式。
So what does he mean by a healthy lifestyle?
那他说的健康生活方式是什么意思？
Well, we don't say life.
嗯，我们不说“生活”。
We say lifestyle because this is the way in which a person lives.
我们说“生活方式”，因为这是一个人生活的方式。
It's your lifestyle.
这是你的生活方式。
Okay.
好的。
So this involves exercise, diet, what kind of food you eat, the way that you work.
所以这包括锻炼、饮食、你吃什么食物、你工作的方式。
Do you get too much sleep?
你睡得太多了吗？
Not enough sleep.
还是睡眠不足。
So your lifestyle is about the choices you make in all parts of your life.
所以你的生活方式关乎你在生活各个方面所做的选择。
And so having a healthy lifestyle, as I said, it's not just about not eating junk food.
所以拥有健康的生活方式，就像我说的，不仅仅是关于不吃垃圾食品。
It's about running five miles or trying to get eight hours of sleep.
还关于跑五英里或努力睡八小时。
So it's important to maintain a healthy lifestyle.
所以保持健康的生活方式很重要。
And usually in the news, we always hear, so usually in the news, we hear this phrase,
通常在新闻里，我们总是听到，所以通常在新闻里，我们听到这个短语，
not healthy life, but healthy lifestyle.
不是“健康生活”，而是“健康生活方式”。
So maybe somebody that leads a dangerous lifestyle maybe has a job that's very dangerous.
所以也许有人过着危险的生活方式，可能有一份非常危险的工作。
That's right.
没错。
Or an unhealthy lifestyle, someone who eats one meal a day.
或者不健康的生活方式，比如有人一天只吃一顿饭。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So those are key phrases for fluency builder.
所以这些是流利度训练的关键短语。
Why don't we go back, listen to the dialogue for the last time, and we'll be back to talk
我们为什么不回去，最后一次听对话，然后我们会回来再跟你们聊一会儿。
with you a little bit more.
再聊一会儿。
Okay, darling, I got some pizzas, potato chips, hot dogs, and lots of cheese.
好的，亲爱的，我买了些披萨、薯片、热狗和很多奶酪。
Oh, John, I thought we said we'd start eating right.
哦，约翰，我以为我们说好了要开始健康饮食。
Remember our new healthy lifestyle.
记得我们新的健康生活方式吗？
That's all junk food.
那全是垃圾食品。
Huh?
啊？
Right.
对。
So what did you get?
那你买了什么？
Well, healthy food, of course.
嗯，当然是健康食品。
I got some whole wheat bread, skimmed milk, fresh fish, and organic carrots.
我买了些全麦面包、脱脂牛奶、新鲜鱼和有机胡萝卜。
Organic?
有机？
What's organic?
什么是有机？
Do we need organic carrots?
我们需要有机胡萝卜吗？
They were grown without using any chemicals that are harmful to our health.
它们是在没有使用任何对健康有害的化学物质的情况下种植的。
And yes, John, we need organic carrots.
是的，约翰，我们需要有机胡萝卜。
Oh, so organic vegetables are the green option, right?
哦，所以有机蔬菜是绿色选择，对吧？
Yep.
是的。
They're good for the environment and better for us.
它们对环境好，对我们也好。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
What's that?
那是什么？
Donuts?
甜甜圈？
Are they organic donuts, Kelly?
凯莉，它们是有机甜甜圈吗？
But I like donuts.
但我喜欢甜甜圈。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So talking about healthy food and healthy eating, how healthy do you eat, Katherine?
所以说到健康食品和健康饮食，凯瑟琳，你吃得有多健康？
I think I eat pretty decently.
我觉得我吃得还算不错。
I try to eat a balanced diet.
我尽量保持均衡饮食。
Like I said earlier, I think a balanced diet is a key to a healthy lifestyle.
就像我之前说的，我认为均衡饮食是健康生活方式的关键。
I don't really eat fast food.
我基本上不吃快餐。
I try not to eat too much meat or too much sugar.
我尽量不吃太多肉或太多糖。
What about organic stuff?
那有机食品呢？
Are you a big fan of organic vegetables, organic meats?
你是有机蔬菜、有机肉类的忠实粉丝吗？
I am.
我是。
And this comes from a part of the dialogue we didn't cover.
这来自对话中我们没覆盖的部分。
One of the characters says that vegetables are the green option.
其中一个角色说蔬菜是绿色选择。
So trying to eat organic food and think about green is a part of thinking about the environment.
所以尽量吃有机食品并考虑绿色是关心环境的一部分。
And so I think eating organic vegetables is an important part of caring about the environment
所以我认为吃有机蔬菜是关心环境的重要部分，
because the more chemicals, the more pesticides we put into the world, the more harmful it
因为我们向世界投入的化学物质和农药越多，对地球、动物和我们自己就越有害。
is for the earth, for animals and for ourselves.
对地球、动物和我们自己就越有害。
Yeah, that's absolutely true.
是的，这绝对是真的。
And it has become a more popular aspect around America and Europe, people choosing to go
这在美洲和欧洲已经成为一个更流行的方面，人们选择吃有机蔬菜，比如在有机农场产的鸡蛋。
with organic vegetables, for example, eggs that were grown on an organic farm.
比如在有机农场产的鸡蛋。
And so it is the healthier option and obviously the green option as we saw in the dialogue.
所以这是更健康的选择，显然也是我们在对话中看到的绿色选择。
Okay, so a very interesting topic.
好的，这是一个非常有趣的话题。
We want to know what your opinion is on it.
我们想知道你对此的看法。
Why don't you come to our website EnglishPod.com and tell us if you are a fan of the light
为什么不来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，告诉我们你是否是清淡或绿色有机生活方式的粉丝，
or green organic lifestyle or maybe you just really don't really care.
或者也许你真的不在乎。
Maybe you love junk food.
也许你爱垃圾食品。
Let us know EnglishPod.com.
在 EnglishPod.com 告诉我们。
All right, we'll see you guys there.
好了，我们那里见。
Bye.
再见。
Thank you.
谢谢。